Finding Aid for the The Sigaux Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Irelande Ireland. Press clippings, periodical, programs, ticket, G. S. notes, journal excerpts. (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Israël (avec point rouge) Israel (with red dot): One folder ("Théâtre"), press clippings, periodical/ book catalog, journal excerpt. Israel: Periodical, printed biographical notecards, letter (to G. S. from Bernard LeCache of the Ligue Internationale Contre le Racisme et l'Antisémitisme), book/publisher's catalog, periodical (inscribed to G. S. by Jean Loewenson), G. S. notes, book and journal advertisement pages, book and journal excerpts. (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Israël (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Italie Italy. Individual folders (general, people, theaters), press clippings, typed transcripts (radio), journal excerpts, G. S. notes, periodicals, program, invitation (to a special Press presentation of Faut Pas Payer by Dario Fo). (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Japon Japan. Individual folders (general, types of theatre, people), journal excerpts, press clippings, program, typed transcript (radio), printed biographical notecard, G. S. notes, book advertisement page. (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Mercier Sebastien Mercier. Typed transcript, books/playtexts. (Box 22, Folder 10)
- Nations "Théâtre des Nations." Journal excerpts, periodical, press clippings, typed transcripts (radio and article), letter (to Paul Blanchart from Phyllis Hartnoll, general editor of Theater Research/Recherches Théâtrales) and attached typed manuscript with handwritten corrections (an article on the Théâtre des Nations). (Box 22, Folder 11)
- New Mexico-80 French Summer School of New Mexico - 1980. Photos (color), postcards, documentation relating to G. S. teaching at the F. S. S. of N. M., periodicals, handmade playbill, G. S. notes, roadmap of Arizona and New Mexico, brochure and receipt of Europ Assistance, typed manuscripts (including photocopies), program/school brochures, professional correspondence (to G. S. from Mathé Allain, from Judith ____?, letters from Claude-Marie Senninger, several photocopies of letters to and from Claude Pichois, and a telegram), personal correspondence (to G. S. from Mme. Patricia Sigaux (?)), press clippings, concert program, opera program and ticket. (Box 22, Folder 12)
- Pixérécourt Guilbert de Pixérécourt. Various booklets/essays by G. de Pixérécourt (Guerre au Mélodrame, Le Mélodrame, Latude, ou Trente-cinq ans de Captivité, Les Ruines de Babylon, ou Giafar et Zaïda, Raymond de Toulouse, ou Le Retour de la Terre Sainte, Le Chateau de Loch-leven.), scraps of handwritten pages, journal excerpt. (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Pologne Poland. Program and other publication of Teatr Groteska, journal excerpts, probram and other publication of Teatr Narodowy, press clippings, various programs and brochures, black and white photograph reproductions, publication of Le Grand Théâtre, periodicals, typed transcripts (radio), G. S. notes, individual folders (personalities). (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Roumanie Romania. Periodical, press clippings, typed transcripts (radio), book and journal excerpts. (Box 23, Folder 3)
- U.R.S.S. U.S.S.R. (Union of the Soviet Socialist Republics / Soviet Union) Press clippings, printed biographical note cards, journal excerpt, book advertisement, typed newsletters from Club des Amis de Preuves, typed transcript (radio). (Box 23, Folder 4)
- U.S.A. Periodicals, book and journal excerpts, printed biographical note card, typed manuscript, G. S. notes, booklet on French writers (in English), typed periodical pages, periodical supplement, book catalog excerpt, periodicals. (Box 23, Folder 5)
- U.S.A.: Auteurs-XXe U.S.A.: Authors-XXth. Press clippings, journal excerpt, individual folders (authors), typed transcript (radio), book advertisements. (Box 23, Folder 6)
- U.S.A.: Gen Press clippings, typed transcripts (articles), airplane brochure, catalog of American books and plays ("forming a history of American theatre"), journal excerpt. (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Objets Divers and Dossier Rouge avec image éxterieur Miscellaneous Items. Book catalogs, bound script of Les Deux Orphelines, Drame en 5 Actes et 8 Tableaux (by A. d'Ennery and F.Corman), books (a dictionary and a writing manual). Red Dossier with exterior image. Book and journal excerpts, press clippings, typed transcripts (radio), G. S. notes, (the general theme of this dossier appears to be more on Theatre as a concept, including places and people). (Box 24)
- Miscellaneous Playtexts (Box 25)
- Étranger - P. A. Quarantotti-Gambini, 1910-1965 (Pier-Antonio Quarantotti-Gambini). Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Salvatore Quasimodo, 1901-1968. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Thomas de Quincey. Press clipping, book catalog excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Ann Radcliffe. Book excerpt, G. S. notes. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Raja Rao. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Gustav Regler. Press clipping, journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Wilhelm Reich. Book or journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - E. M. Remarque (Erich Maria Remarque). Journal excerpts, press clippings, handwritten notes (not G. S.). (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Alexei Remizov. Journal excerpts. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Alfonso Reyes. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Ladislas Reymont, 1867-1925. Press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Peter Rhodes. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Jean Rhys. Press clippings, book advertisement page. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Richardson (Samuel Richardson). Typed transcript (radio), book advertisement, book excerpt (Clarisse Harlowe par Jules Janin. 1846, Librairie D'Amyot, Éditeur, Paris). (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Conrad Richter. Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - J. P. Richter (Jean-Paul Richter). Journal excerpts, press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Dionisio Ridruejo. Journal excerpt, newsletter (Preuves Informations). (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Louise Rinser. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Harold Robbins. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - George Rodenbach. Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Frederick Rolfe. Book advertisement pages, press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - D. G. Rossetti (and Christina Rossetti). Journal excerpt, book advertisements (catalog). (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Edwin Rosskam. Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Henry Roth. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Philip Roth. Press clippings, journal excerpts, book advertisement page). (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - A.-L. Rowse (loose item). Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Vassili Rozanov. Press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Adolf Rudnicki. Journal excerpts, press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Damon Runyon. Journal excerpts (including a typed transcript), book advertisement page. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - John Ruskin. Journal excerpt, press clippings, typed transcript (radio). (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Bertrand Russell. Journal excerpts, press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Étranger - Irvin Shaw. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Robert Shaw. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Percy Bysshe Shelley. (loose item) Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Mary Shelley. Book excerpt (preface), press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Friedrich Sieburg. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Henry Sienkiewicz (Henryk Sienkiewicz / Henri Sienkiewicz). Press clippings, G. S. notes. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - F. E. Silanpää (F. E. Sillanpää). Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Allan Sillitoe. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Clifford D. Simak. Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Constantin Simonov, 1915-1979. Press clippings, book advertisement pages, book jacket excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Upton Sinclair. Press clippings, journal excerpt, notes (G. S.?), book excerpt (preface for 1948 edition of Manassas, translated by Roger Bertin). (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Andrew Sinclair. Book advertisement page, press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Issac B. Singer. Journal excerpts, press clippings, book advertisement pages, typed newsletter (from Informations Stock). (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - André Siniavski. Journal excerpts, press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Edith Sitwell. Book advertisement page. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Osbert Sitwell. G. S. notes. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Frank Slaughter. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Christopher Smart. Book or journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Sergei Smirnov. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Wallace Smith. Book advertisement page. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Tobias Smollett. Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - C. P. Snow (Charles Snow). Journal excerpts. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Vladimir Socoline. Book advertisement page. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Ardengo Soffici, 1879-1964. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Mario Soldati. Journal excerpts, press clippings, book advertisement pages. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Susan Sontag. Press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Castro Soromenho. Newsletter (Preuves Informations). (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Muriel Spark. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Stephen Spender. Press clippings, journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Leo Spitzer. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Marguerite Steen. Book advertisement page. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Wallace Stegner. Press clipping, typed manuscript (brief biography). (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Edith Stein. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Gertrude Stein. Press clippings, journal excerpts (including typed transcripts/newsletters - Arts et Lettres), book catalog and advertisement pages, G. S. notes. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Étranger - John Steinbeck. Book dust jacket with G. S. notes, press clippings, journal excerpts, book advertisement page. (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Georges Steiner. Press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Rudolf Steiner. Press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Sterne (Lawrence Sterne). Press clippings, journal excerpts, book catalog excerpt, G. S. notes. (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Wallace Stevens. Typed transcript (article). (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Adalbert Stifter. Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Bram Stoker. Press clippings, journal excerpts, typed manuscript (by Christopher Lee). (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Theodore Storm. Typed transcript (radio). (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Lytton Strachey. Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Étranger - William Styron. Journal excerpts, press clippings, book excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Abraham Sutzkever. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Han Suyin. Printed biographical notecards, typed transcript (radio), journal excerpts, press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Italo Suevo, 1861-1928. Press clippings, journal excerpts, typed transcript (radio), book catalog and advertisement pages. (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Swift (Johnathan Swift). Journal excerpts, press clippings, book advertisement and catalog pages. (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Swinburne (Algernon Charles Swinburne). Book catalog page, journal excerpt, press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Arthur Symons. Journal excerpt, press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Rabindranath Tagore. Press clippings, book advertisement page. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Tibor Tardos. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Valery Tarsis. Press clippings, newsletter (Preuves Informations). (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Booth Tarkington. Book dust jacket. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Peter Taylor. Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Korneï Tchoukovski, 1882-1969. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Tchoukovskaia (Lydia Tchoukovskaia). Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Teffi. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Luca de Tena (Torcuato Luca de Tena). Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Tennyson (Alfred Tennyson). Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - W. M. Thackery, 1811-1863. Book excerpt, journal excerpts, press clipping, correspondence (to G. S. from ?), G. S. notes. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Dylan Thomas. Journal excerpts, press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Henri David Thoreau (Henry David Thoreau), 1817-1862. Journal excerpts, press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - James Thurber. Journal excerpts. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Ludwig Tieck. Typed transcript (radio). (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Nicolas Tikhonov. (loose item) Book advertisement page. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Alice Tisdale Hobart. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Alexis Tolstoï. Journal excerpts, book advertisement page, press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Jaime Torres Bodet, Mexicain. Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Tourguéneff (Ivan Tourguéneff / Ivan Tourguéniev). Correspondence (to G. S. from Alexandre Zviguilsky), press clippings, book advertisement (bookmark), G. S. notes, photocopy of a newsletter/bulletin (Association des Amis d'Ivan Tourguéniev). (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Arnold Toynbee (Arnold Joseph Toynbee). Press clippings, journal excerpts. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Georg Traki, 1887-1914. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - B. Traven (Bruno Traven). Press clippings, typed bibliography. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Iouri Trifonov. (loose item) Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Anthony Trollope, 1815-1882. Journal excerpts. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Trotzky (Léon Trotzky / Léon Trotski). Journal excerpt, press clipping, book advertisement page. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Franz Tumler. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Alexandre Tvardoski. Press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Mark Twain. Journal excerpts, press clippings, G. S. notes, book advertisement page). (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Youri Tynianov. Press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Étranger - Miguel de Unamuno. Press clippings, journal excerpts (including an off-print), book advertisement pages. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Étranger - Sigrid Undset, 1882-1949. Book advertisement pages, journal excerpts, typed transcript (radio). (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Étranger - Giuseppe Ungaretti. Press clippings, book advertisement pages, journal excerpts. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Étranger - Fritz von Unruh. Journal excerpts. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Étranger - John Updike (folder 1). Journal excerpts, press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Étranger - John Updike (folder 2). Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Étranger - Valle-Inclan (Ramon de Valle-Inclan). Journal excerpts, press clippings, typed transcript (radio). (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Étranger - Benjamin Valloton. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Étranger - Vassilis Vassilikos. Journal excerpt, press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Étranger - Giovanni Verga. Press clipping, journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Étranger - Guido da Verona. Jouranl excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Étranger - Gore Vidal. Press clippings, journal excerpts. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Étranger - Villalonga (José-Luis de Villalonga). Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Étranger - Elio Vittorini, 1909-1966. Press clippings, typed transcript (radio). (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Étranger - Vonnegut (Kurt Vonnegut). Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Étranger - Paolo Volponi. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Étranger - John Wain. Press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Margaret Walker. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Edgar Wallace. Journal excerpts, book advertisement and catalog pages. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Lewis Wallace, 1827-1905. Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Irving Wallace. Journal excerpts. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Horace Walpole. Journal excerpts, typed transcript (radio). (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Hugh Walpole, 1884-1940. Book advertisement page, typed manuscript (iography), periodical (The Hogarth Letters, No. 9), typed manuscript with corrections ("Lettre à un Romancier Moderne" par Hugh Walpole). (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Martin Walser. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Robert Walser. Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Rex Warner. Press clippings, G. S. notes, typed transcript (article, British Council Overseas Press Dept., 6-12-45). (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Jacob Wassermann, 1873-1934 (Jakob Wassermann). Press clippings, journal excerpts, G. S. notes, book advertisement pages. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Hugo Wast. G. S. notes. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Alan Watts. Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Evelyn Waugh. Journal excerpts, press clippings, book jacket excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Mary Webb. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Denton Welch. Book advertisement page, journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Dieter Wellershoff. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Franz Werfel. Press clipping, G. S. notes, notes in a different hand. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Morris West. Journal excerpt, press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Nathanaël West. Book excerpt, press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Edith Wharton, 1862-1937. Press clippings, book advertisement excerpts, journal excerpts. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Patrick White. (loose item) Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - S. E. White, 1873. G. S. notes, press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Walt Whitman. Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Étranger - Ernst Wiechert. Book advertisement pages, press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Elie Wiesel. Press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Thornton Wilder. Book excerpt, press clipping, journal excerpts. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - William Carlos William (William Carlos Williams). Press clipping, typed newsletters (Arts et Lettres), typed manuscript (photocopy, "J'ai voulu écrire un poème" (extraits)). (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Angus Wilson. Press clippings, journal excerpt, typed newsletter (Informations Stock). (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Colin Wilson. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Edmund Wilson. Press clippings, journal excerpts, book advertisement page. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Kathleen Winsor. G. S. notes. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - P. G. Wodehouse (Pelham-Grenville Wodehouse). Journal excerpts, press clippings, G. S. notes, printed biographical notecard, typed bibliography (french translations). (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Heinrich Wolfflin. Typed manuscript (-Heinrich Wolfflin-"Rennaisance et Baroque"). (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Thomas Wolfe. Journal excerpts, G. S. notes, press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Wordsworth. Journal excerpts. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Richard Wright, 1908-1960. Press clippings, journal excerpt, typed excerpt (article?). (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - W. B. Yeats (William Butler Yeats). Press clippings. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Mishima Yukio. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Atahualpa Yupanqui. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Lin Yutang. Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Eugene Zamiatine (Yevgeny Zamaytin). Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Israël Zangwill. (loose item) Typed bibliography (french translations). (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Cesare Zavattini. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Thadée Zelenski, Boy-Zelenski. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Alexandre Zinoviev. Journal excerpts, press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Victor Zoctowski. Journal excerpt. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Fritz Zorn. Press clipping. (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Arnold Zweig. Press clippings, G. S. notes, book excerpts (includes photocopies), typed partial bibliography, typed biography and bibliography (outline). (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Étranger - General material relating to Foreign Literature (non-French). Book and journal excerpts, press clippings, book advertisement and catalog pages, printed biographical notecard, newsletters (Club des Amis de Preuves, Preuves Informations, and Société Européenne de Culture) (Box 27, Folder 7)
- Étranger - Isaac Babel. Press clippings, journal excerpt. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Dorothy Baker. Book advertisement pages. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Angelica Balabanoff. Press clipping. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - James Baldwin. Book adveristement pages, press clippings. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Arturo Barea, 1897-. Journal/book excerpt. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Maurice Baring. Journal excerpts, book advertisement pages, press clippings, G. S. notes. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Natalie Clifford Barney. Journal excerpts, press clippings. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Pio Baroja. Journal excerpts, book advertisement page, press clippings. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - John Barth. Press clipping. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Vicki Baum. Journal excerpt, G. S. notes, notes in a different hand. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Sylvia Beach. Press clippings. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Aubrey Beardsley. G. S. notes, book advertisement and catalog pages, press clippings, journal excerpts. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - William Beckford. Press clippings, G. S. notes. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Mrs. Beecher-Stowe (Harriet Elizabeth Beecher-Stowe). Newsletter (Édito Service, S. A.), book excerpts (photocopies), typed bibliography (of french translations), 2 typed manuscripts (La Case d'Oncle Tom: "Introduction" and "Portée de l'oeuvre"). (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Peter Belloc. Book advertisement page. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Saul Bellow (Saül Bellow). Press clippings, journal excerpts, book advertisement page. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Stephen Vincent Benèt, 1898-1943. Journal excerpt. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Walter Benjamin. Press clippings, journal excerpts. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Gottfried Benn. Journal excerpts. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Arnold Bennett. Press clippings. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Bernard Berenson. Book advertisement page, press clippings. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - J. D. Beresford (John Davys Beresford). Handwritten notes. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - José Bergamin. Typed transcript (radio), press clippings. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Werner Bergengruen (Werner Bergengrün). Journal excerpt. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Giuseppe Berto. Press clipping. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Étranger - Andrei Biély. Press clippings. (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Ambrose Bierce. G. S. notes, journal excerpts, press clippings, book advertisement page. (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Lesley Blanch. Press clipping, book advertisement page. (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Étranger - William Blake. Book advertisement card, press clippings, journal excerpt, typed manuscript ("Un Indépendant: Introduction à William Blake". (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Karen Blixen. Press clippings, journal excerpt. (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Ernst Bolch. Press clippings, G. S. notes, book advertisement page. (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Alexandre Blok. Journal excerpts. (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Enid Blyton. Press clipping. (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Étranger - Boccace (Giovanni Boccaccio). Journal excerpt. (Box 27, Folder 3)